Since the two main Attention papers were published in 2014 and '15,
因为这两篇主要论文是在 2014 和 2015 年发表的
Attention has been an active area of research with many developments.
注意力一直是个比较活跃的研究领域 出现了很多新的发展
While the two mechanisms continue to be commonly used,
虽然这两个机制一直都是常用机制
there have been significant developments over the years.
但是这几年出现了重大发展
In this video, we will look at one of
在这个视频中 我们将讲解其中一篇论文
these developments published in a paper titled Attention Is All You Need.
叫做“Attention Is All You Need”
This paper noted that the complexity of encoder-decoder with Attention models can be
这篇论文指出 具有注意力机制的编码器-解码器模型的复杂性
simplified by adopting a new type of model that only uses Attention, no RNNs.
可以通过采用一种新的模型来简化 这种模型仅使用注意力 不使用 RNN
They called this new model the Transformer.
他们将这种新模型称为 Transformer
In two of their experiments on machine translation tasks,
在两项机器翻译任务实验中
the model proved superior in quality
该模型都呈现出极高的质量
as well as requiring significantly less time to train.
并且训练时间大大缩减
The Transformer takes a sequence as an input and generate a sequence,
Transformer 将序列作为输入并生成序列
just like the sequence-sequence models we've seen so far.
和我们到目前为止见到的序列-序列模型一样
The difference here, however,
但是区别在于
that it does not take the inputs one by one,
它并不像 RNN 那样
as in the case of an RNN.
逐个地获取输入
It can produce all of them together in parallel.
它可以并行地生成所有输入
Perhaps each element is processed by a separate GPU if we want.
如果可以的话 可以用单独的 GPU 处理每个元素
It then produces the output one by one but also not using an RNN.
然后逐个地生成输出 也不使用 RNN
The Transformer model also breaks down into an encoder and a decoder.
Transformer 模型也由编码器和解码器组成
But instead of RNNs,
但使用的不是 RNN
they use feed-forward neural networks and a concept called self-attention.
而是前馈神经网络和自注意力机制
This combination allows the encoder and decoder to work without RNNs,
这种组合使编码器和解码器不需要使用 RNN
which vastly improves performance since it allows
这样可以显著改善性能
parallelization of processing that was not possible with RNNs.
因为可以并行处理 而这一点 RNN 却做不到
The Transformer contains a stack of identical encoders and decoders.
Transformer 包含一组相同的编码器和解码器
Six is the number the paper proposes.
这篇论文推荐 6 对
Let's focus on the encoder in more layer and look at it more closely.
我们重点看看包含一个层级的编码器并仔细研究下
Each encoder layer contains two sublayers: a
每个编码器层级包含两个子层级
multi-headed self-attention layer and a feed-forward layer.
一个多头自注意力层级和一个前馈层级
As you might notice,
你可能注意到了
this Attention component is completely on the encoder side as
这个注意力组件完全位于编码器一端
opposed to being a decoder component like the previous Attention mechanisms we've seen.
而不像之前的注意力机制那样 在解码器端也有
This Attention component helps the encoder comprehend its inputs by focusing on
这个注意力组件通过侧重于与要处理的每个输入元素
other parts of the input sequence that are relevant to each input element it processes.
相关的输入序列的其他部分 帮助编码器理解输入
This idea is an extension of work previously done on
这种理念是对自注意力概念雏形的延伸
the concept of self-attention and how it can aid comprehension.
有助于理解输入
In one paper, for example,
例如 在一篇论文中
this type of Attention is used in the context of machine reading,
这种注意力用在了机器阅读中
where the experiments on this technique matched or outperformed
这种技巧的实验结果与
the state of the art at that time in tasks like language modeling,
当时针对某些任务的最先进技术的效果相当或表现更好
sentiment analysis and natural language inference.
这些任务包括语言建模 情感分析和自然语言推理
They still used RNNs but they augmented it with
他们依然使用了 RNN
this idea that later became self-attention.
但是利用这种概念进行了增强 后来发展成自注意力
The example they used in this machine reading
他们在这个机器阅读论文中使用的示例
paper shows where the train model pays attention as it reads each word.
展示了训练模型在阅读每个单词时 将注意力集中在何处
So, for example, when the model reads the sentence using an LSTM,
例如 当模型使用 LSTM 阅读这个句子时
it learns which other parts of the input to pay
它学会了在处理输入的每个单词时
attention to as it processes each word of the input.
应该注意输入的哪些其他部分
So, the red is where it's reading and the blue is
红色表示正在阅读的位置
where it's paying attention as it's reading this word.
蓝色表示阅读这个单词时注意力集中的位置
At each step, it reads a word and it pays attention to
在每一步 它都阅读一个单词
the relevant previous words that would aid in comprehending that word.
并注意到有助于理解该单词的前面相关单词
The structure of the Transformer, however,
但是 Transformer 的结构
allows the encoder to not only focus on previous words in the input sequence,
使编码器不仅能够侧重于输入序列中之前的单词
but also on words that appeared later in the input sequence.
而且能够注意到之后出现的单词
This, however, is not the only Attention component in the Transformer.
但是这个并不是
The decoder contains two Attention components.
解码器包含两个注意力组件
One that allows it to focus on the relevant part of
一个使其能够侧重于输入的相关部分
the inputs and another that only pays attention to previous decoder outputs,
另一个仅注意到之前的解码器输出
and there you have it.
就这样
A high-level view of the components of the Transformer.
这就是 Transformer 组件的概览
We can see how extensively this model uses Attention.
可以看出这个模型大量使用了注意力机制
We can see three Attention components here.
这里有三个注意力组件
They don't all work exactly the same way,
它们并非行为完全一样
but they all boil down pretty much to multiplicative attention,
但是差不多都是乘法注意力
which we already understand.
我们已经讲过这种注意力